Andre Azzolini

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

apazzolini@gmail.com | https://azzolini.io

I'm a full-stack engineer in Dallas, TX that specializes in modern JS development. I view programming as a craft to be appreciated not only for the end product, but also for the code itself. There's a strong link between the elegance and simplicity of a codebase and its correctness, performance, and adaptability.

Experience

MVPindex (Lead Developer)

Mar. 2016 - Present

- Designed and programmed a robust framework (Kafka, Node is) for ingesting hundreds of millions of social network posts.
- Optimized query performance by introducing a multi-node Elasticsearch cluster and Pilosa with near-real-time syncing.
- Created an internal dashboard (React v16, websockets) to monitor ingestion and jobs status, history, and logs.
- Exposed access to data via a permission-driven API (Hapi) used by the Insights app, the admin app, and customers directly.
- Architected a jobs framework and implemented several jobs to ensure data quality and perform various ETL tasks.
- Mentored junior developers and improved the workflow for feature estimation, paying off tech debt, and bug triage.
- · Reduced infrastructure expense by 5 figures on AWS by consolidating servers and converting deployments to utilize Docker.

Freelancer Oct. 2014 — Mar. 2016

- Managed a Scala team in automating flows for a telecommunication company's ordering system.
- Designed an integration testing framework to facilitate CI for a large Dockerized microservices project.
- · Created a web application from a Material Design specification for interfacing with Cisco telephony equipment.
- Implemented a real-time interface for managing touchscreens used for directory services in commercial buildings.
- Led a team and architected a customizable dashboard that integrated internal systems for a health services company.

Broadleaf Commerce (Senior Engineer)

Oct. 2011 — Oct. 2014

- Designed and implemented several large, key components of the Broadleaf Commerce codebase
- Oversaw multiple concurrent client implementations and fostered positive, ongoing relationships.
- · Self-prioritized time between client support, client implementations, framework development, and framework bugfixes.

Credera (Consultant) May 2010 — Oct. 2011

- Programmed multiple subsystems of an eCommerce site for a Fortune 1000 company with Java, Spring, and HTML/CSS/JS.
- Performed various infrastructure tasks including tuning Apache Tomcat, handling deploys, and debugging production issues.
- · Trained several new team members on general application structure and the various technologies utilized in the project.

Skills

- Frontend: ES2018, React, Redux, Immutable.js, Jest, Babel/Webpack, CSS3/SASS, HTML5
- Backend: Node.js, Hapi, Express, Kafka, Aurora/MySQL, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, Java, Spring, Hibernate, Scala, Akka
- Devops: Unix, OS X, AWS, Docker, Gitlab, CI/CD, deployment configuration, server management, security/cryptography
- · Languages: English (native speaker), Portuguese (fluent spoken, working knowledge written)

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

December 2010

Bachelor degrees in Computer Science and Management Information Systems